If there is one thing in life that we could choose not to experience, it is the death of someone we love.
如果说人生中有一件事是我们宁愿选择不经历的，那一定是挚爱之人的离世。
Losing a friend or family member is heartbreaking and hard to accept, but how we deal with it, and how we ‘move on’, varies from person to person.
失去朋友或亲人的滋味令人心碎，也让人难以接受，但每个人应对这种伤痛、走出阴霾的方式都不尽相同。
Death is, of course, inevitable, but sometimes we feel the passing of a loved one has come too soon.
死亡固然是不可避免的，但有时我们会觉得挚爱之人的离去实在太过仓促。
Our first reaction is to grieve, and even though we may soon be encouraged to accept closure and let go, the grieving can last a while.
我们的第一反应往往是陷入悲痛，即便很快就会有人劝我们放下过去、释怀告别，这份悲伤却可能持续许久。
But grief is a very natural, human response to loss and can take the form of many unexpected emotions, from shock to guilt, anger and disbelief.
但悲伤本就是人类面对失去时的自然反应，它会以各种意想不到的情绪呈现，从震惊、愧疚到愤怒、难以置信，不一而足。
When someone dies, we may be tempted to put on a brave face and hide our feelings.
当亲人离世时，我们可能会忍不住故作坚强，把内心的痛苦藏起来。
But experts say that this is the time to talk about feelings – even cry and sob and show people you are suffering.
但专家表示，这个时候恰恰应该倾诉心声——哪怕是放声大哭，让别人知道你正在承受的煎熬。
There’s nothing wrong with trying to keep the memory of the deceased alive.
想方设法留住对逝者的记忆，本就无可厚非。
You can talk to them in your head, write them a letter or share memories with other people who knew them.
你可以在心里和他们对话，写一封信寄往天国，或是和其他认识他们的人一起分享回忆。
Some people have chosen to make a more permanent reminder of someone by getting a memorial tattoo.
有些人会选择纹纪念纹身，以此作为对逝者永恒的念想。
Dr John Troyer from Bath University told the BBC: “You can have a continuing bond with the dead…
巴斯大学的约翰·特罗耶博士在接受BBC采访时表示：“你可以和逝去的人保持一种持续的联结……
I think it’s a very important way for people to come to terms that someone’s left.”
我认为这是人们接受离别事实的一种非常重要的方式。”
Whatever approach you take to grieving and to keeping someone’s memory alive, eventually the physical aching and pain caused by the loss of a loved one will subside.
无论你选择以何种方式哀悼逝者、留存记忆，这份因失去挚爱而带来的生理与心理的痛楚，最终都会慢慢消退。
But the memories of that person and the times we shared can stay with us forever, and talking about them and expressing your feelings is all part of the healing process.
但关于那个人的记忆，以及我们共度的时光，却会永远留在心底。倾诉思念、表达情绪，都是治愈过程中不可或缺的一部分。
But as singer and songwriter Patti Smith told the BBC: “Loss is something that we never get over.”
正如创作型歌手帕蒂·史密斯在接受BBC采访时所说：“失去这件事，我们永远都无法真正释怀。”